<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>BASED COOKING</title>
	<link>https://henryiscooking.com/tags/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Tags on BASED COOKING</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-gb</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:42:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://henryiscooking.com/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>Cheat Demi Glace</title>
		<link>https://henryiscooking.com/cheat-demi-glace/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:42:40 +0100</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://henryiscooking.com/cheat-demi-glace/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;Demi-glace is a rich, meaty sauce that can be used as the foundation for other sauces.This preparation yields multiple, frozen demi-glace cubes that can be used like a stock cube to kick-start a pan sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It traditionally uses veal which can be quite hard to find. This is a simpler version which produces pretty close results and can be done in way less time with the help of a pressure cooker. An added benefit of pressure cooking is that no skimming is required during cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ingredients--mise-en-place&#34;&gt;Ingredients &amp;amp; mise en place&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use ~3.5kg total meat/bones - whatever you can find is fine but the chicken wings are recommended for its gelatin content. Optionally, substitute the chicken wings for powdered gelatin and a different cut of meat. Depending on the size of your pressure cooker, you can use less/more water but I would recommend the same amount of total meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional: powdered gelatin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2kg chicken wings if not using powdered gelatin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5kg beef shank or beef bones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 onions, roughly chopped (optional: keep outer skin but remove any dirt on roots if dirty)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 carrots, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 tbsp tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 garlic cloves, gently crushed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thyme sprigs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 litres water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure cooker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large roasting tray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sieve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ice cube trays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prep roasting tray with oil, tomato paste, vegetables and meat/bones. Start pressure cooker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add vegetables and bones to pressure cooker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure cook on high for 90 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skim and strain the solids out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cool stock and refrigerate overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skim solidified fat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce to half of the original volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour into ice cube trays and freeze overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop demi-glace out of ice cube trays into a freezer friendly bag and keep frozen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 240°C (220°C convection).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liberally oil a large roasting pan with vegetable oil. Place chopped onions and carrots into pan. Drizzle tomato paste over the vegetables and mix well. Place meat/bones on top of vegetables. The tomato paste adds umami and it is crucial to not let the paste burn, as its burned taste is potent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roast in oven for ~45 minutes, before turning the meat/bones and exposing lighter coloured parts. Continue roasting until a deeply browned, approximately 30-40 more minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the bones are roasting, pour in the water, garlic gloves, thyme sprigs and bay leaf into the pressure cooker and start heating until it reaches a simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the roasting pan out of the oven and carefully transfer all of its contents into the pressure cooker. If there is any fond stuck, deglaze with water and use a wooden spoon to scrape up as much as possible, then transfer to the pressure cooker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pressure cook for 90 minutes on high pressure. Allow the pressure to be released naturally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the pressure cooker lid and discard all of the solids, optionally using a collander. Strain the contents through a sieve back into a heat-resistant container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the container into a cold water bath to help cool the stock down quickly, or leave the container outside if it&amp;rsquo;s cold, before refrigerating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When fully cooled, skim off the fat with a spatula and discard, while preserving as much stock as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat the stock in a pan to reduce its volume by about half.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the stock carefully into ice cube trays with a ladle. Once the stock is at ambient temperature, place the trays into the freezer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the demi-glace stock cubes are frozen, pop them out into a freezer bag and keep in the freezer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
